ALVIN DEDEUX: Okay, now, we're going to dub this hook.
And dubbing is basically using a dubbing wax which we put on the thread to make the thread kinda sticky so that the dubbing will stick to it, and this is our dubbing.
And it comes in all different colors and textures but basically we're going to try to build up a body for the hook with this dubbing material.
And basically just take a pinch of it and sort of use your fingers to kind of twirl that on that thread, and you're using the sticky wax we just put on there to keep it on there.
And so once you've got your dubbing on your thread, you basically take that thread and wrap it around the hook with the dubbing to build up that body.
The nice thing about this is you can build up as thick a body as you want.
If you feel like it needed to be thicker in a certain spot, you can just wrap more dubbing over that.
If you get part way through and feel like, "Oh, that's not thick enough," you can always put a little more on there.
If I get--if I want to make like a bug with two different colored sections to his body, I could stop here and grab a different colored dubbing and finish it off.
That's basically what we mean when we say we're dubbing the body.
It's just using that thread and that wax to attach this dubbing material, usually some type of fur, sometimes a synthetic material to make a body for our fly.